Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：
是的，是的，船长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
Mmm...
嗯...
Ahh...
啊...
Mwah.
哇。
I know I've said this
90 times already but...
我知道我已经说过了
已经90次了但是...
♪ I love Krabby Patties ♪
♪ 我喜欢蟹黄馅饼 ♪
♪ I think that they are swell ♪
♪ 我觉得他们很膨胀 ♪
♪ They are the best ♪
♪ 他们是最棒的 ♪
♪ There's no contest ♪
♪ 没有竞争 ♪
♪ And now I'm going to yell ♪
♪ 现在我要大喊 ♪
Whoo.
呼。
♪ I love Krabby Patties ♪
♪ 我喜欢蟹黄馅饼 ♪
♪ I think they're swell ♪
♪ 我觉得他们很膨胀 ♪
♪ They're so neat ♪
♪ 它们真整齐 ♪
♪ And quite a treat ♪
♪ 真是一种享受 ♪
♪ And, oh, I love
they way they smell ♪
♪ 而且，哦，我爱
他们的气味 ♪
♪ La, la ♪
♪ 啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la... ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦……♪
I know I shouldn't have
gotten out of bed today.
我知道我不应该
今天起床了。
♪ La... la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦...啦啦啦啦 ♪
Hello...
你好...
and welcome one and all your
money to ye old Krusty Krabby.
并欢迎您的一位和所有
钱给你们老库斯蒂·克拉比。
Come along, sisters.
姐妹们快来吧。
Pay not mind to this
crimson abomination.
不用在意这个
深红色的憎恶。
Ahh...
啊...
Greetings.
问候。
Although your
establishment
seems repugnant
虽然你的
设立
似乎令人反感
and foul in nature,
且性质恶劣，
it seems not to offend
our sensitivities.
似乎并没有冒犯
我们的敏感性。
It is for that reason
plus the fact that
正是因为这个原因
再加上事实
we have been stuck on a tour bus
for several days
我们被困在旅游巴士上
好几天
that my sisters and I would
like to eat something here.
我和我的姐妹们会
喜欢在这里吃东西。
OK, but first let me
call the mortician
好的，但首先让我
打电话给殡仪师
and tell him his
uniform's been stolen.
并告诉他他的
制服被偷了。
Clothing zinger.
服装劲爆。
Squidward,
these wretched hags...
章鱼哥，
这些可恶的女巫……
Uh... Lovely ladies
呃……可爱的女士们
are obviously here to eat.
显然是来吃饭的。
So let's sell 'em...
所以我们把它们卖掉吧...
Uh, I mean, serve them some
delicious Krabby Patties.
呃，我的意思是，给他们提供一些
美味的蟹肉饼。
Well, Mr. uh...
嗯，呃先生...
Krabs, m'lady.
螃蟹，女士。
Mr. "Grabs".
“抢”先生。
You seem to know the basic rules
你似乎知道基本规则
of behaving like
a civilized bottom feeder.
表现得像
文明的底层喂食者。
Perhaps your
restaurant isn't quite
也许你的
餐厅不太好
the hive of degenerates
it appears to be
堕落者的巢穴
看来是
and we had you
figured all wrong.
我们有你
都想错了。
Course you did.
当然你做到了。
As you're about to find out.
正如你即将发现的那样。
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Ahh...
啊...
♪ I like Krabby Patties ♪
♪ 我喜欢蟹黄饼 ♪
♪ I think they're swell ♪
♪ 我觉得他们很膨胀 ♪
♪ I like Krabby Patties ♪
♪ 我喜欢蟹黄饼 ♪
♪ Can you not tell? ♪
♪ 你能说不出来吗？ ♪
♪ Krabby Patties,
Krabby Patties ♪
♪ 蟹肉饼，
蟹肉饼♪
♪ They're so neat ♪
♪ 它们真整齐 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ Sweet to eat ♪
♪ 吃起来甜甜的 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ Really neat ♪
♪ 真的很整洁 ♪
♪ Sweet to eat ♪
♪ 吃起来甜甜的 ♪
♪ Treat that's neat ♪
♪ 对待它很整洁 ♪
♪ Sweet treat ♪
♪ 甜点 ♪
♪ Treat, sweet, treat, sweet ♪
♪ 款待，甜蜜，款待，甜蜜 ♪
♪ Hickory, trick or treat ♪
♪ 山核桃木，不给糖就捣蛋 ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo, doo ♪
♪ 嘟、嘟、嘟、嘟 ♪
♪ Ra-ta-ta-ta,
ta-ta-ta-ta ♪
♪ 拉塔塔塔，
塔塔塔塔♪
♪ Ta-ta-ta-ta,
ta-ta-ta-ta ♪
♪ 塔塔塔塔塔，
塔塔塔塔♪
♪ Ta-ta-ta-ta-doo ♪
♪ 塔塔塔塔杜 ♪
♪ Ra-ta-doo, ra-ta-doo ♪
♪ 拉-塔-杜，拉-塔-杜 ♪
♪ Ra... dah ♪
♪ 拉...达 ♪
♪ La, la, la, la ♪
♪ 啦，啦，啦，啦 ♪
♪ La... ♪
♪ 啦... ♪
♪ La, la,
la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦，啦，
啦啦啦啦♪
Sss...
嘶……
Look at this wild hooligan
看看这个狂野的流氓
running amok.
胡作非为。
Singing, dancing.
唱歌、跳舞。
It's... It's shameless
and disgusting.
这……真是无耻啊
和恶心。
Avert your eyes.
移开你的目光。
Young man...
年轻人...
what has caused you
to act like this?
是什么导致了你
这样做？
I must know.
我必须知道。
Actually ma'am...
其实女士...
was the absolute fun and
deliciousness of a Krabby Patty.
绝对有趣而且
蟹肉饼的美味。
Krabby Patty?
克拉比·帕蒂？
Yeah,
that's right.
是的，
没错。
Well, anything this fun and
delicious can't be good.
好吧，任何如此有趣和
美味不可能是好的。
Why, what would this world be
为什么，这个世界会是什么样子
if everyone cavorted
in such a manner?
如果每个人都欢闹
以这样的方式？
Who are you
with your tight lips
你是谁
用你紧闭的嘴唇
raised eyebrows
and conservative clothes?
扬起眉毛
和保守的衣服？
I am Miss Gretel Puss.
我是格蕾特·普斯小姐。
We are The United
Organization of Fish
我们是联合
鱼的组织
Against Things That
Are Fun And Delicious.
反对那些事
既有趣又美味。
Or TU-O-FATTAFAD for short.
或简称 TU-O-FATTAFAD。
And we are going to ban
these so-called Krabby Patties
我们将禁止
这些所谓的蟹肉饼
and close your
restaurant forever.
并关闭你的
永远的餐厅。
What the...
什么...
Miss "Gristle" Puss?
“软骨”猫小姐？
Maybe if you were to taste
the Krabby Patty for yourself
也许如果你想尝尝
为自己准备一份蟹肉饼
you two could experience
the awesome pleasure.
你们两个可以体验
令人敬畏的快乐。
I would soon as sprout legs
and do the Watusi.
我很快就会长出腿
并做瓦图西。
Ooh, OK.
哦，好吧。
Uh, it don't matter
anyway, lad.
呃，没关系
无论如何，小伙子。
She can't close us down.
她不能让我们关闭。
Krabs: She closed us down.
螃蟹：她关闭了我们。
I'm ruined...
我毁了...
How did it
come to this?
是怎么做到的
来到这个？
You called Miss Gristle Puss
a disgusting, old prune
你叫格里斯托小姐为小猫
令人作呕的老李子
then you threatened her
with a French fry strainer.
然后你威胁她
用炸薯条过滤器。
Well, I didn't know her
husband was the chief of police.
嗯，我不认识她
丈夫是警察局长。
Thanks again, Al.
再次感谢，阿尔。
Anytime, honey.
任何时候，亲爱的。
See you at home for dinner.
晚上回家见。
Mm, I'm starving.
嗯，我饿了。
Yee-haw.
呀呀。
I just love that man.
我就是爱那个男人。
How long has he
been standing over there?
他多久了
一直站在那儿吗？
Um... Four days.
嗯……四天。
It's no use.
这是没有用的。
I'm ruined...
我毁了...
You know, it's too bad.
你知道，这太糟糕了。
The only way to make
Krabby Patties again
唯一的办法就是制作
又是蟹肉饼
would be if you
opened a place that didn't
look like a restaurant
如果你会
开了一个没有的地方
看起来像一家餐馆
and did it secretly.
并且是秘密进行的。
That's it.
就是这样。
A secret Krusty Krab.
秘制蟹堡王。
And I know just
where to open it.
我知道只是
在哪里打开它。
There you are, Betsy,
good as new.
你在这里，贝特西，
完好如新。
Mmm...
嗯...
Mr. Krabs?
蟹老板？
Whoa, sorry.
哇，抱歉。
I was just wondering...
我只是想知道...
You know, lad,
I can remember a time
你知道，小伙子，
我记得有一次
when people used to knock before
entering someone else's home.
以前人们敲门的时候
进入别人家。
Yeah, but this is my home.
是的，但这是我的家。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
Hey, guys.
嘿，伙计们。
Hey, Patrick.
嘿，帕特里克。
Thanks for helping out today.
谢谢你今天帮忙。
You bet.
你打赌。
Where'd you want
these extras buns?
你想要去哪里
这些额外的面包？
Patrick, that bag
is totally empty.
帕特里克，那个包
完全是空的。
... Oops.
... 哎呀。
Plankton: Happy day, Karen.
浮游生物：快乐的一天，凯伦。
That fool, Krabs, changed
the name of his restaurant
蟹蟹那个傻瓜变了
他的餐厅的名字
to "The Closed Krab".
到“封闭的螃蟹”。
Everyone will
think it's closed
每个人都会
认为它已关闭
and come eat here instead.
那就来这里吃饭吧。
He'll be ruined by tomorrow.
明天他就会被毁掉。
Heh-heh, what an idiot.
呵呵，真是个白痴啊。
It is closed.
它已关闭。
What?
什么？
Miss Gristle Puss
and her husband
克里斯特尔猫小姐
和她的丈夫
banned Krabby Patties
for being fun and delicious.
禁止蟹肉饼
因为有趣又美味。
Banned?
被禁止？
Then that means
那么这意味着
my day of reckoning
has come at last.
我的清算日
终于来了。
I've won, I tell you,
I've won.
我赢了，我告诉你，
我赢了。
And what better way
than by default.
还有什么更好的方法
比默认情况下。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Oh, out to celebrate.
哦，出去庆祝一下。
Don't wait up for me.
别等我了
Quit shoving.
别再推搡了。
I wasn't shoving.
我没有推搡。
I was just going like that
我就这样走了
and you happened
to be standing there.
你发生了
站在那里。
That's called shoving.
这就是所谓的推搡。
No, it isn't.
不，不是。
Yes, it is.
是的。
Nope.
没有。
But what's with
all the hullabaloo?
但有什么关系
所有的喧嚣？
We're just waitin' in line
to buy a Krabby Patty.
我们只是在排队等待
买蟹肉饼。
Krabby Patty?
克拉比·帕蒂？
Thank you.
谢谢。
Come again.
再来吧。
Patrick: Can I help whoever
is next, please?
帕特里克：我可以帮助谁吗
请问是下一个吗？
Patrick: What's the
password, please?
帕特里克：那是什么
请问密码？
What are you talking about
你在说什么
you gargantuan buffoon?
你这个大小丑？
That's it.
就是这样。
Come right in.
进来吧。
Curse you.
诅咒你。
Meow.
喵。
So would you like to "secret"
size that for $2 more?
那么你想“秘密”吗？
尺寸要多 2 美元吗？
Of course.
当然。
Hey, "Squidwart"?
嘿，“鱿鱼疣”？
You haven't seen any sign
of the... you know...
你还没有看到任何迹象
的...你知道...
the cops, have you?
警察，你有吗？
Did you just
call me "Squidwart"?
你刚刚是不是
请叫我“鱿鱼”？
OK, thanks, I'm gonna go
see how SpongeBob's doing.
好的，谢谢，我这就去
看看海绵宝宝的表现如何。
Hey, SpongeBob...
嘿，海绵宝宝...
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Ohh...
哦...
What are you doing
under the table?
你在做什么
在桌子底下？
If Krabby Patties
are illegal now
如果蟹肉饼
现在是非法的
aren't we breaking the law?
我们没有违法吗？
There's an old saying, lad.
有句老话，小伙子。
What doesn't kill you
什么杀不死你
usually succeeds
in the second attempt.
通常会成功
在第二次尝试中。
But what does that have to
do with making Krabby Patties?
但这有什么必要
做蟹黄馅饼吗？
Nothing, but if you don't get
out there and start cooking
没什么，但如果你没有得到
在那里开始做饭
I'll make you start
taking weekends off.
我会让你开始
周末休息。
SpongeBob: No!
海绵宝宝：不！
So Mr. Krabs is operating
所以蟹老板正在操作
under the table, huh?
在桌子底下吧？
Well, two can play at that game.
嗯，那个游戏可以两个人玩。
Being a ruthless mastermind
sure takes a lot out of you.
成为无情的主谋
肯定会让你付出很多。
Man: Hello, this is
Officer Al, Chief of Police
男：你好，这是
艾尔警官，警察局长
Cops, I need you.
警察们，我需要你们。
There.
那里。
What's the pass...
通行证是什么...
Nope, that's not it.
不，不是这样的。
You missed one.
你错过了一个。
Oh, Miss Gristle Puss.
哦，格里斯托猫小姐。
I'm sorry we sold Krabby Patties
抱歉我们卖掉了蟹黄饼
but do you really have
to send us to jail?
但你真的有吗
把我们送进监狱？
Of course, I do.
当然，我愿意。
You are a nuisance
to my community.
你真是个麻烦
到我的社区。
You tell 'em, honey.
你告诉他们，亲爱的。
Ha... That's my girl.
哈...那是我的女孩。
: Al.
：阿尔。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Having some lunch.
吃点午饭。
Unhand that
sandwich at once.
松开那个
立即三明治。
Miss Gristle Puss, look out.
格里斯托猫小姐，小心。
What?
什么？
Your shoe's untied.
你的鞋带解开了。
It is?
这是？
Ohh...
哦...
: Ohh...
: 哦...
Ahh...
啊...
♪ I like Krabby Patties ♪
♪ 我喜欢蟹黄饼 ♪
♪ I think they're swell ♪
♪ 我觉得他们很膨胀 ♪
♪ Can you not tell? ♪
♪ 你能说不出来吗？ ♪
♪ Krabby Patties,
Krabby Patties ♪
♪ 蟹肉饼，
蟹肉饼♪
♪ They're so neat ♪
♪ 它们真整齐 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la,
la-la-la-la-la... ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦，
啦啦啦啦啦……♪
Really neat, ha...
真的很整齐，哈...
♪ Sweet to eat ♪
♪ 吃起来甜甜的 ♪
♪ Treat that's neat ♪
♪ 对待它很整洁 ♪
Both: ♪ Ra-ta-ta-ta,
ta-ta-ta-ta ♪
两者：♪ 拉塔塔塔，
塔塔塔塔♪
♪ Ta-ta-ta-ta-doo ♪
♪ 塔塔塔塔杜 ♪
... Blah.
... 废话。
♪ And dismount. ♪
♪ 然后下马。 ♪
That was wonderful.
那太棒了。
I... I feel...
我……我感觉……
reborn.
重生。
Does this mean you're not
sending us to the slammer?
这是否意味着你不是
把我们送去监狱？
Of course, my dear boy.
当然，我亲爱的孩子。
I am a kinder, gentler fish
我是一条更善良、更温柔的鱼
and I owe it all to you.
我把这一切都归功于你。
Don't forget the spatula.
别忘了抹刀。
Don't push it, Al.
别逼它，艾尔。
Darn it.
该死的。
Ahh.
啊。
Once again,
so close and yet so far.
再一次，
如此接近，却又如此遥远。
When am I gonna...
我什么时候才能...
Ooh.
哦。
Well, I think
I'll have another one.
嗯，我想
我再要一份。
Oh, dear.
哦亲爱的。
Plankton: Ahh!
浮游生物：啊！
Hey...
嘿...
Somebody left me a package.
有人给我留下了一个包裹。
: Heavy.
： 重的。
I wonder what's inside?
我想知道里面是什么？
Hello.
你好。
Whew... cramped in there.
呃……那里很拥挤。
Cousin Stanley.
斯坦利表弟。
Cousin SpongeBob.
海绵宝宝表弟。
La-la-la-la...
啦啦啦啦……
So what brings you
to Bikini Bottom, Stanley?
那么是什么给你带来
去比基尼泳裤吧，斯坦利？
Uncle Sherm said
I should come visit you.
谢姆叔叔说
我应该来拜访你。
I have a note from him
somewhere... Oh, right.
我有他的便条
某处...哦，对了。
It's in here.
它就在这里。
Here it is.
这里是。
"Dear SpongeBob.
“亲爱的海绵宝宝。
I'm sending your cousin Stanley
to live with you.
我要派你的表弟斯坦利来
和你住在一起。
He can't hold down a job
他保不住工作
and he ruins
everything he touches.
他毁了
他接触到的一切。
I can't take it anymore.
我再也受不了了。
Maybe you can
straighten him out.
也许你可以
把他摆正。
Love, Uncle Sherm."
爱你，谢姆叔叔。”
Well, you're always
welcome here Stanley.
嗯，你总是
欢迎来到斯坦利。
My pineapple is your pineapple.
我的菠萝就是你的菠萝。
Wow, you've got
your own refrigerator.
哇，你有
你自己的冰箱。
I'm not allowed near the
'fridge at Uncle Sherm's.
我不被允许靠近
“谢姆叔叔家的冰箱。”
Whoa...
哇...
SpongeBob: Oh, well...
海绵宝宝：噢，好吧……
Now I won't have
to clean it out.
现在我不会有
把它清理掉。
Stanley: Wha-hoo-hoo-hoo.
斯坦利：哇-呼-呼-呼。
Stanley?
斯坦利？
You OK in there, Stanley?
你在里面还好吗，斯坦利？
Your toilet is so cool.
你家厕所好酷啊
Is that what I think it is?
是我想的那样吗？
Well, it was bath night.
嗯，那是洗澡之夜。
TV Announcer: Only $29.95.
电视播音员：仅需 29.95 美元。
Gee, whee...
哎呀，哎呀...
Uncle Sherm won't
let me watch TV back at home.
雪姆叔叔不会
让我回家看看电视。
Why not?
为什么不呢？
That's why.
这就是原因。
What's that?
那是什么？
Oh, that's OK.
哦，没关系。
There's nothing
good on TV anyway.
什么都没有
无论如何，电视上都很好。
Nothing.
没有什么。
You work at the Krusty Krab?
你在蟹堡王工作吗？
I don't just work there.
我不只是在那里工作。
I'm vice-assistant,
general manager
我是副助理
总经理
in charge of certain things.
负责某些事情。
That's me turning
the front door key.
那是我转身
前门钥匙。
That's me serving customers.
这就是我为顾客服务的情况。
And that's me performing
sanitary maintenance.
这就是我表演的
卫生维护。
Ooh, who's that?
哦，那是谁？
Oh, that... That's me
making Krabby Patties.
噢，那个……那是我
制作蟹黄饼。
The best job in the world.
世界上最好的工作。
It's my calling.
这是我的召唤。
I wish I had a calling.
我希望我有一个电话。
Aw, Stanley...
噢，斯坦利……
You just haven't found your
purpose in life, that's all.
你只是还没有找到你的
人生目标，仅此而已。
You really think so?
你真的这么认为吗？
I know so.
我知道是这样。
I'll bet my friend,
Squidward, can help you.
我敢打赌我的朋友
乌贼，可以帮助你。
Hi, Squidward.
嗨，章鱼哥。
I'd like you to meet
my cousin Stanley.
我想让你认识一下
我的表弟斯坦利。
We're related.
我们有关系。
Squidward: There's two of them?
章鱼哥：有两个？
Step on it.
踩它。
Your friend, Squidward,
seems busy.
你的朋友，章鱼哥，
看起来很忙。
No, that's OK.
不，没关系。
I'm sure Sandy
can think of something.
我确信桑迪
能想到一些东西。
Sandy: Hey, SpongeBob..
桑迪：嘿，海绵宝宝..
who's your friend?
谁是你的朋友？
This is my cousin,
Stanley SquarePants.
这是我的表弟，
斯坦利方裤。
I thought you could show him
how to be a scientist.
我以为你可以给他看
如何成为一名科学家。
Why, sure.
为什么，当然。
Glad to meet you, partner.
很高兴认识你，伙伴。
Nice to meet you...
很高兴见到你...
Uh...
呃...
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
Y'all darn it...
你们都该死...
Uh... Maybe you're just
not scientist material.
呃...也许你只是
不是科学家材料。
But don't you worry.
但你不用担心。
I'll bet Patrick
can help ya.
我敢打赌帕特里克
可以帮助你。
He's a genius.
他是个天才。
SpongeBob: And so Mr. Star,
that's why we came to you.
海绵宝宝：所以星星先生，
这就是我们来找你的原因。
Looking for
your calling, huh?
寻找
你的电话，是吗？
Hmm...
唔...
Um-hm.
嗯嗯。
So what are you good at?
那么你擅长什么？
Nothing.
没有什么。
Nothing at all?
什么都没有？
Yup.
是的。
Interesting.
有趣的。
Let's see how
good you are at nothing.
让我们看看如何
很好，你一无是处。
That's perfect.
那很完美。
Patrick can do nothing
better than anyone.
帕特里克无能为力
比任何人都好。
You'll be learning
from the master.
你将会学习到
来自大师。
Come with me.
跟我来吧。
First sit down in this chair.
首先坐在这把椅子上。
Clear your mind.
清理你的头脑。
Empty it of all thoughts
清空一切思绪
until you're doing
直到你在做
absolutely...
绝对地...
nothing.
没有什么。
Gah...
嘎……
See? Isn't he amazing?
看？他不是很了不起吗？
Clear my mind.
理清我的思绪。
Do nothing.
什么也不做。
Ahh...
啊...
I can't do it!
我做不到！
You're not worthy of instruction
in the immobile arts.
你不值得教导
在不动的艺术中。
Leave my presence.
离开我的存在。
Couldn't I try...
我就不能尝试一下吗...
Not a word.
一言不发。
Dah...
呸……
Stanley: I can't even
do nothing right.
斯坦利：我什至不能
什么都不做。
Don't give up Stan-O.
不要放弃斯坦-O。
We just need
to keep looking.
我们只需要
继续寻找。
Oh, gentle hat.
哦，温柔的帽子。
Symbol of employment.
就业的象征。
Cornerstone of
my eternal happiness.
的基石
我永恒的幸福。
I don thee now in preparation
for this work day.
我现在给你做准备
为了这个工作日。
Whoo...
呼...
You have no idea
how good this feels.
你不知道
这感觉多好啊。
: No...
： 不...
Hey, what's wrong, Stanley?
嘿，怎么了，斯坦利？
You're not still upset
over that whole
你还没有不高兴
在整个
"never accomplished anything
in life" thing, are you?
“从未完成任何事情
生活中的事情，你是吗？
No...  .
不...  。
Good, then why don't you
come with me to work.
很好，那你为什么不呢
跟我一起去上班吧。
Maybe seeing me totally
fulfilled will cheer  you  up.
也许完全看到我
满足会让你高兴起来。
There's me little
money maker.
有我一个小
赚钱机器。
Mm, mm, mm...
嗯，嗯，嗯……
Are you gonna make me
lots of money today?
你要让我
今天有很多钱吗？
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
Ooh, what'd I give
if only there were two of...
哦，我给了什么
要是有两个就好了……
What?
什么？
One, two?
一、二？
There's two?
有两个吗？
He looks like ya.
他看起来像你。
He smells like ya.
他闻起来像你。
He tastes like ya.
他的味道像你。
Is he a hard worker
just like you?
他是一个勤奋的人吗
就像你一样？
Um...
嗯...
Duh... Eh...
呃……呃……
Well, is he?
嗯，是吗？
Please, please, please, please
拜托，拜托，拜托，拜托
please, please, please,  please.
拜托，拜托，拜托，拜托。
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
You got the job.
你得到了这份工作。
Your job is to
take people's money
你的工作是
拿人家的钱
and put it in here.
并把它放在这里。
Whoa, can I touch it?
哇，我可以摸一下吗？
Money?
钱？
Burning?
燃烧？
SpongeBob, who's
responsible for this?
海绵宝宝，谁是
对此负责？
I...
我...
...guess I am, Mr. Krabs.
...我猜是的，蟹老板。
You're on probation, boy.
你正处于缓刑期，孩子。
Well, Stanley,
thanks to you
嗯，斯坦利，
谢谢你
I'm on probation.
我正在试用期。
If you wanna keep this job
如果你想保住这份工作
you're gonna have to...
你必须...
Ooh...
哦...
Customer at the port bow.
顾客在左舷鞠躬。
Man your stations.
管理你的车站。
Ready for duty.
准备值班了。
My first customer.
我的第一个顾客。
Hi, I'm Stanley.
嗨，我是斯坦利。
Whoa... This is  so  exciting.
哇...这太令人兴奋了。
Huh, I'd like a...
呵呵，我想要一个...
Wait-Wait,
wait-wait, hold on.
等等等等，
等等等等，等等。
I don't ever wanna
forget this moment.
我永远不想
忘记这一刻。
That's gonna be a keeper.
那将成为一名守门员。
Now let's do one
with funny hats.
现在我们来做一个
带着滑稽的帽子。
Ooh, yeah, let's pretend
we're mad at each other.
哦，是的，我们假装
我们对彼此很生气。
I can't wait to get
these developed.
我等不及想要得到
这些发展起来了。
SpongeBob: I said
I'm ready, Stanley.
海绵宝宝：我说
我准备好了，斯坦利。
SpongeBob, what's
the meaning of this?
海绵宝宝，什么
这是什么意思？
Your station
looks horrible.
你的电台
看起来很可怕。
Take some pride
in your work, boy.
有点自豪感
在你的工作中，孩子。
Look at your cousin,
Stanley, for example.
看看你的表弟，
以斯坦利为例。
Spiffin' up his work space
整理他的工作空间
with meaningful photos
of the customers.
并附上有意义的照片
的客户。
Um... sir?
嗯……先生？
Yes, boy?
是的，男孩？
About my cousin Stanley.
关于我的表弟斯坦利。
Yes, yes, the one I hired
entirely on your recommendation.
是的，是的，就是我雇的那个
完全根据您的推荐。
Hurry it up, boy.
快点吧，男孩。
Uh, well...
Actually, sir?
呃，好吧...
事实上，先生？
About those things I said?
关于我说的那些事？
What?
什么？
You didn't lie to me
你没有骗我
just to help your cousin
get the job, did you?
只是为了帮助你的表弟
得到这份工作，是吗？
No.
不。
Well, good...
嗯，很好...
Because there were plenty
of other relatives
因为有很多
其他亲戚的
that got passed
over for the job.
已经通过了
结束工作了。
Aye, 'tis true.
是的，这是真的。
Whatever.
任何。
I even turned down me own
three adorable nephews.
我什至拒绝了我自己
三个可爱的侄子。
But
但
Krabs.
螃蟹。
They solve mysteries.
他们解开谜团。
Now go solve the mystery of
why you didn't get the job.
现在就去解开谜底
为什么你没有得到这份工作。
Stanley...
斯坦利...
I cannot keep
covering for...  you!
我无法保留
为……你掩护！
: No...
： 不...
Not my spatula.
不是我的锅铲。
My spatula.
我的锅铲。
The thing I hold nearest
and dearest to my heart.
我拿着最近的东西
我最亲爱的。
SpongeBob, what in the name
of Neptune has got...
海绵宝宝，叫什么名字
海王星有...
Oh, you broke
your spatula.
哦，你坏了
你的抹刀。
That's a shame.
太可惜了。
I'll order another
one tomorrow, boy.
我再订一份
明天就有一个，孩子。
No, no, no!
不，不，不！
I  didn't break my spatula.
我没有弄坏抹刀。
He  did.
他做到了。
And I also didn't
burn your money.
而我也没有
烧掉你的钱。
He did that, too.
他也这么做了。
I have been covering for him
我一直在替他掩护
because he can't
do anything right!
因为他不能
做任何事都正确！
He's right  .
他是对的。
I ruin everything I touch.
我毁掉了我接触到的一切。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
I know the perfect
job for you.
我知道完美
为你工作。
Good luck at your new
job today, Cousin Stanley.
祝你新的好运
今天工作，斯坦利表弟。
Thanks.
谢谢。
I'll bet I'm even
better at this one.
我敢打赌我什至
更擅长这一点。
Good morning,
Mr. SquarePants.
早上好，
方裤先生。
Morning, boss.
早上好，老板。
I can't believe it.
我简直不敢相信。
That fool Krabs,
letting the blood relative
蟹蟹那个傻瓜，
让血亲
of his best worker...
他最好的工人...
Well, that's the end of me.
好吧，我的事就这样结束了。
Sorry, boss.
对不起，老板。